让我们总结一下我们在本讲座中学到的东西。
Let’s summarise what we have learned in this lecture.
MATLAB支持矩阵和标量，矩阵和矩阵之间的许多操作。
MATLAB supports a number of operations between matrices and scalars, and matrices and matrices.
在矩阵和标量的情况下，会发生的是标量应用于每个标量
In the case of a matrix and a scalar, what happens is that the scalar is applied to every
输入矩阵的元素和那些结果被放入相应的元素中
element of the input matrix and those results are placed into the corresponding elements
输出矩阵
of the output matrix.
我们可以在矩阵和标量之间使用的各种运算符包括标准
The sorts of operators we can use between a matrix and a scalar include the standard
算术运算符，它们还包括逻辑运算符，它们执行逻辑运算
arithmetic operators and they also include the logical operators, which perform logical
比较，其结果是假的。
comparisons, and which have a result which is either true of false.
当我们在矩阵和矩阵之间执行操作时，矩阵需要是
When we perform an operation between a matrix and a matrix, the matrices need to be the
相同的大小和操作在矩阵的相应元素之间执行。
same size and the operations are performed between corresponding elements of the matrix.
结果被放入输出矩阵的相应元素中。
Results are placed into the corresponding element of the output matrix.
MATLAB支持许多逻辑运算符。
MATLAB supports a number of logical operators.
逻辑运算符的结果只是真或假，我们可以执行许多不同的结果
The results of logical operator are only true or false and we can perform a number of different
逻辑测试：平等;非平等;比...更棒;少于;等等。
logical tests: equality; non-equality; greater than; less than; and so on.
我们已经谈到了monadic图像处理，这就是单个像素的位置
We have talked about monadic image processing and that is where individual pixels in the
输入图像通过函数f（x）传递，结果放入相应的
input image are passed through a function f(x) and the result is placed into the corresponding
输出矩阵中的元素。
element in the output matrix.
我们对所有像素应用相同的函数，我们查看了许多操作，例如
We apply the same function to all pixels and we looked at a number of operations such as
对比;增强;亮度变化;直方图归一化;阈值;色调分离;
contrast; enhancement; brightness change; histogram normalization; thresholding; posterization;
等等。
and so on.
而且还有很多很多。
And there are many, many, more.
我们所看到的另一类操作就是我们所说的diadic操作
The other class of operation we looked at are what we called diadic operations and here
我们有两个输入图像，通过一个函数并输出值
we have two input images, passed through a function and the output value is placed into
输出图像中的相应像素。
the corresponding pixel in the output image.
diadic操作的一些例子是图像减法，我们用它来找到差异
Some examples of diadic operations were image subtraction, which we used to find the difference
在两个输入场景之间。
between two input scenes.
我们还使用了不同的diadic操作的数量来执行相当复杂的操作
We also used the number of different diadic operations in performing quite a sophisticated
图像处理任务，即实现绿屏效果。
image processing task, which is implementing the green screen effect.